const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",t="accounting",o=200,i=120,a=[{id:213,question:"The art of collecting, recording, presenting and interpreting accounting data is",option:{a:"cost accounting",b:"management accounting",c:"financial accounting",d:"data processing."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:166,question:"Which of the following expenses relate to the profit and loss account of a manufacturing firm?",option:{a:"Administrative overhead.",b:"Direct labour",c:"Direct materials.",d:"Work-in-progress."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:450,question:"The amount of subscriptions accrued is reported in the balance sheet under",option:{a:"fixed asset",b:"long-term liability",c:"current asset",d:"current liability."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:494,question:"Apart from the common control accounts, a control account can also be opened for",option:{a:"sales account",b:"purchases account",c:"cash account",d:"wages account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:247,question:"Using the reducing balance method, the depreciation charged for year 2003 was",option:{a:"N  160,000",b:"N  150,000",c:"N   130,000",d:"N  120,000"},section:"Motor vehicles (at cost) 1/1/2002   [N1,000,000],  Addition to motor vehicles 1/7/2003  [N  600,000] 	Depreciation rate 10%",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:417,question:"Where the debit side of the income and expenditure account is higher than the credit side, the difference is",option:{a:"deficit",b:"surplus",c:"gain",d:"loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:146,question:"The major sources of revenue for the state and local governments is",option:{a:"value added tax",b:"statutory allocation",c:"taxes and levies",d:"recurrent revenue."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:396,question:"A debit in the suspense account will appear in the balance sheet as",option:{a:"a current asset",b:"a current liability",c:"capital",d:"drawings"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:186,question:"Which of the following is an advantage of the imprest system?",option:{a:"Making high profits in the business",b:"Rewarding the imprest holder",c:"Easy preparation of the final accounts",d:"Meeting small items of expenditure"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:122,question:"Stock account is a type of",option:{a:"nominal account.",b:"personal account.",c:"real account.",d:"fixed assets account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:22,question:"If a   machine   cost   2000   naira   and its estimated   life   span   is   10   years   and its residual is 500 naira. The yearly value of depreciation  in  naira is ",option:{a:"250",b:"180",c:"150",d:"130"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:427,question:"The accounting entry to record the premium on goodwill is to debit",option:{a:"cash and credit old partners’ capital",b:"goodwill and credit revaluation",c:"assets and credit capital",d:"capital and credit assets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:504,question:"Which of the following is a common cause of a discrepancy between head office and branch trial balance?",option:{a:"Debtors and cash in transit",b:"Creditors and cash in transit",c:"Stock and cash in transit",d:"Stock and prepayments"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:381,question:"A company made a net profit of N2,000,000 for the year and its net profit percentage is 25%. What is the total sales   for the year?",option:{a:"N8,000,000",b:"N6,000,000",c:"N800,000",d:"N500,000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:354,question:"Which of the following is used to record the disposal of a fixed asset?",option:{a:"Journal  Proper",b:"Petty  Cash  Book",c:"Sales Day Book",d:"Purchases Day Book"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:178,question:"A Receipt and Payments Account reveals",option:{a:"net profit",b:"surplus",c:"cash in hand",d:"gross profit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:173,question:"A suspense account is used to",option:{a:"agree the trial balance",b:"record sales",c:"record purchases",d:"correct errors"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:473,question:"How much is sundry expenses?",option:{a:"N 2 700",b:"N 2,250",c:"N1,550",d:"N2000."},section:"Given: Returns inwards [N1, 500]; Cash [N1, 550]; Discount received [N2, 850]; Capital [N3, 800 ]; Debtors [N900];	Sundry expenses [  ?  ]; 	The value of sundry expenses is 150% of returns inwards plus 50% of debtors.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:265,question:"The process of entering transaction from one book to another is",option:{a:"reading.",b:"posting.",c:"numbering",d:"listing"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:241,question:"A set of instructions fed into a computer for accomplishing a given task is a/an",option:{a:"input",b:"programme",c:"output",d:"data."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:296,question:"Which of the following is found in a Memorandum of 	Association?",option:{a:"Names of directors",b:"Appointment of directors",c:"Object of the business",d:"Payment of dividend"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:362,question:"The sum of direct cost in a manufacturing account is",option:{a:"production cost",b:"prime cost",c:"total cost",d:"finance cost"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:298,question:"Which of the following is not a revenue to a local government?",option:{a:"Fines",b:"Licenses",c:"Personal income tax",d:"Tenement rates"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:308,question:"Goods returned to a supplier is",option:{a:"debited to Returns outwards account",b:"credited to Returns outwards account",c:"debited to Returns inwards account",d:"credited to Returns inwards account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:44,question:"A company provided the following information about its balance sheet: Cash N100 Accounts receivable N500 Stockholders' equity 14700 Account payable N200 Bank loans Nl000 Based on the information provided, how much are Remington's liabilities?",option:{a:"N200   ",b:"N900   ",c:"N 1,200   ",d:"N 1,700"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:228,question:"In company accounts, profit after tax is shared in the",option:{a:"appropriation account",b:"revaluation account",c:"current account",d:"realization account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:505,question:"Sule and Ahmad are in partnership sharing profits and losses equally. If  Khadija is admitted as a new partner to take 1/5 th as her share, what is the new profit or loss sharing ratio?",option:{a:"Sule1/3 , Ahmad 1/3 and Khadija 1/3",b:"Sule1/5, Ahmad 1/5 and Khadija 3/5",c:"Sule2/5,  Ahmad2/5 and Khadija 1/5",d:"Sule ,2/5, Ahmad and 1/5 Khadija 2/5"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:32,question:"A cheque which has been sent but has yet gone through the bank account of the receiver of it is known as:",option:{a:"Dishonoured cheque",b:"Unpresented cheque ",c:"Uncredited cheque",d:"Unhonoured cheque"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:51,question:"Which of the following accounts would be classified as a current on the balance sheet?",option:{a:"Office Equipment",b:"Accumulated Depreciation",c:"Land",d:"Accounts receivable"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:162,question:"When the purchase Consideration is lower than the net asset, the buyer has gained the advantage of",option:{a:"capital reserve",b:"revenue reserve",c:"net-income",d:"net loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:456,question:"The federal government approved  N 140 m to local governments W, X, Y and Z. The amount is to be shared on the basis of 40% equality. 35% population and 25% internal revenue generation. Calculate the share of local government W on equality.",option:{a:"N 35 m",b:"N 14 m .",c:"N 56 m",d:"N 28 m."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:235,question:"“A business unit is assumed to operate into foreseeable future and earn reasonable net income”. This statement is emphasized by the concept of",option:{a:"business entity",b:"going concern",c:"realization",d:"accrual."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:229,question:"Which of the following is not a source of revenue to a government?",option:{a:"Taxation",b:"Sale of goods",c:"Imposition of fines",d:"Grants"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:469,question:"The process whereby a cheque received by one person is given to another for payment is known as",option:{a:"cheque crossing",b:"payment in cheque",c:"cheque transfer",d:"cheque endorsement."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:113,question:"A set of instructions or programs which controls the operation of a computer is",option:{a:"software.",b:"hardware.",c:"monitor.",d:"keyboard."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:239,question:"Prime cost is",option:{a:"D120,500",b:"D117,700",c:"D114,900",d:"D114,300."},section:"Given Opening stock:  raw materials [10,000 ], work-in-progress [16,000],  Purchases of raw materials [95,500] , Direct labour wages paid [13,500], Royalties paid [6,200], Accrued wages[2,800], Closing stock- raw materials [7,500], work-in-progress[ 8,500], 	Manufacturing overhead [10,000]",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:58,question:"If a business shows a debit balance in its own record of its bank balance, this indicates.",option:{a:"The business has a bank overdraft",b:"The business is a debtor of the bank",c:"The business has money in the bank",d:"The ledger entry must be wrong."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:249,question:"The amount allowed off the cost price of an article to stimulate patronage is",option:{a:"cash discount",b:"trade discount",c:"discount on debt",d:"discount on bills."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:434,question:"A company has departments X, Y and Z. Department X occupies a space twice that of Y while Z   occupies half the space of  Y. If the company pays N 70 000 on rent, what is the amount of rent that should be allocated to Y?",option:{a:"N 30,000",b:"N 40,000",c:"N 20,000",d:"N 10, 000."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:158,question:"Purchases can be ascertained through the preparation of a",option:{a:"stock account",b:"sales account",c:"total debtors’ control account",d:"total creditors, control account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:253,question:"The balance as per bank statement is",option:{a:"D10,900",b:"D8,400",c:"D5,600",d:"D2,800"},section:"Balance as per cash book [8,400], Bank charges [300], Standing order paid [2,500 ], Unpresented cheques [2,800]",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:277,question:"Rent accrued in 2009 was D140. In 2010, D900 was paid while D160 was outstanding. Rent for 2010 was",option:{a:"D1,200.",b:"D1.060.",c:"D920.",d:"D880."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:262,question:"A fixed asset fully written-down by a trader is now considered to be worth N5,000. The double entry required to effect       this is: debit",option:{a:"Asset Account; credit Purchases Account.",b:"Asset Account; credit Capital Account.",c:"Capital Account; credit Asset Account.",d:"Capital Account; credit Profit and Loss Account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:8,question:"At the end of a trading period, wages will be  ",option:{a:"debited to trading account and shown as a current liability ",b:"credited to profit and loss Account and shown as a current liability ",c:"credited to trading account and shown as a current asset ",d:"debited to profit and loss account and shown as a current liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:464,question:"The amount to be charged to the profit and loss account is",option:{a:"N 30,000",b:"N25,000",c:"N 5 ,000",d:"N20,000."},section:"Given: Prepaid b/f [N10, 000 ]; Cash paid during the year  [N20, 000]; Prepaid c/f [N5, 000] ",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:421,question:"Discounts granted to branch customers are treated as a debit to branch",option:{a:"stock account and a credit to branch debtors’ account",b:"discount account and a credit to branch bank account",c:"stock account and a credit to branch bank account",d:"discount account and a credit to branch debtors’ account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:205,question:"Where there are no proper books of account, the capital at the commencement of a period is ascertained by preparing",option:{a:"Total Debtors and Creditors Accounts",b:"Bank Reconciliation Statement",c:"Statement of Affairs",d:"Trading, Profit and Loss Accounts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:337,question:"Which of the following expenses is allocated according to the floor 	area?",option:{a:"Wages and Salaries",b:"Rent and rates",c:"Canteen expenses",d:"Discount allowed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:2,question:"A credit note from a supplier would first be entered in the ",option:{a:"purchase book  ",b:"sales book  ",c:"returns inward book  ",d:"returns outward"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:55,question:"The essential amount of depreciation or equipment for a period is 2,000 the adjusting end to record depreciation would be",option:{a:"Debit depreciation expense, 2000, credit expense, 2,000",b:"Debit equipment, 2,000; credit depreciation expense, 2,000",c:"Debit accumulated depreciation, 2,000. credit depreciation expense 2,000    ",d:"Debit depreciation expense, 2,000; credit accumulated depreciation 2,000."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:282,question:"Partners whose liabilities are restricted to their financial contribution to the partnership in the event of winding up are",option:{a:"ordinary partners",b:"limited partners",c:"dormant partners",d:"sleeping partners"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:426,question:"When a new partner is admitted to a partnership, there is a need to revalue the",option:{a:"capital of the business",b:"capital and liabilities of the business",c:"assets and capital of the business",d:"assets and liabilities of the business"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:431,question:"According to the provisions of the 1999 Constitution, all revenues generated by the Federal Government must be paid into the?",option:{a:"Consolidated Revenue Fund",b:"Federation Account",c:"Revenue Mobilization Allocation and Fiscal Commission’s Account",d:"Equalization Fund"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:345,question:"The source document used to make entries in the purchases day book is",option:{a:"debit note",b:"credit note",c:"invoice",d:"receipt"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:333,question:"How much was paid for goodwill?",option:{a:"GHc/ 350,000",b:"GHc/ 260,000",c:"GHc/  90,000",d:"GHc/ 60,000"},section:"Use the following information to answer questions: Mr. White acquired Mr. Black’s business for GHc/ 410,000. The total assets were GHc/ 670,000 and liabilities amounted to GHc/ 320,000",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:501,question:"What is the accumulated fund?",option:{a:"23,700",b:"27,750",c:"29,650",d:"51,650"},section:"Given: Furniture and fittings [N 20,000]  Equipment [N15,000] Bank overdrafts [ N6,500] Bar creditors [ N4,800 ] Subscription in arrears [ N4,700 ] Subscription in advance [ N650]",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:243,question:"Which of the following is charged to trading account?",option:{a:"Discounts allowed",b:"Carriage outwards",c:"Salaries",d:"Carriage inwards."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:10,question:"A company's profit and loss account for a period  is  prepared by ",option:{a:"deducting total expenses from total revenues ",b:"deducting total cash payments from total revenue ",c:"deducting  all  outflows  of funds  from  all inwards of funds ",d:"balancing its receipts and payments"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:278,question:"Which of the following is not an input device?",option:{a:"Card reader",b:"Paper top reader",c:"Alpha-numeric keyboard",d:"Line printer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:156,question:"From the information above, sources of income for a Not-for-profit making organization include",option:{a:"I, III, IV",b:"I, II, III",c:"I, II, IV",d:"I and IV"},section:"I.   Members subscription II.  Fines  from members  III. Donation  IV.  Loan from bank",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:75,question:" Impersonal accounts contain ",option:{a:"capital and cash account ",b:"nominal account and real account ",c:" real and cash account ",d:"capital and real act minis "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:56,question:"Which of the following assets could be described as a current asset?",option:{a:"Stock of goods for resale",b:"Machinery to manufacture goods for resale ",c:" Buildings to house the machinery",d:"Land on which the buildings stand."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:443,question:"Goods worth N 50 000 were sent at different times from head office to the branch during the year. By the end of the period, only N  40 000 worth of goods had arrived at the branch. Which of the following is correct about the treatment of this transaction?",option:{a:"Branch should debit goods received from head office with N 50 000.",b:"Head office should debit goods sent to branch account with N 10 000.",c:"Head office should debit goods sent to branch account with N 50 000.",d:"Branch should debit goods received from head office with N  10000."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:256,question:"Rent expenses for the year 2005 is",option:{a:"N 11,400",b:"N  11,300",c:"N  11,200",d:"N  10,200."},section:"Rent accrued 1st January, 2005 [600], Rent paid in 2005 [11,300], Rent prepaid 31st December, 2005 [500]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:465,question:"The purchases ledger control account showed a credit balance of N 525 000 on April 30, 2006. This amount shows",option:{a:"what the debtors of a business enterprise owed the business",b:"the total amount which each debtor owed the business",c:"what a business enterprise owed its creditors",d:"the total amount which a business enterprise owed each creditor."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:347,question:"In the operation of an imprest system of petty cash, the",option:{a:"petty cashier pays all expenses",b:"petty cashier pays money to the accountant",c:"petty cashier regularly begins each period with the same amount of money",d:"main cashier accounts to the petty cashier for some expenses made by him"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:154,question:"Which of the followings is a credit item in creditors ledger control account?",option:{a:"Returns outwards.",b:"Discount Received.",c:"Bad debts.",d:"Purchases."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:167,question:"The difference between book keeping and accounting is that while",option:{a:"book keeping interprets data accounting records it",b:"book keeping is regarded as  the language of the business, accounting ascertains its .strength and weakness",c:"book keeping records data accounting interprets it",d:"book keeping - summaries information, accounting communicates it."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:400,question:"Zakari started a business on January 2000. He bought a shop costing N 54,000 and stock worth N 7,600.  Profit for the year amounted to N 22,100. His closing capital was N 73,800. Zakari’s personal drawings amounted to",option:{a:"N 2,300",b:"N9,900",c:"N 17,100",d:"N 19,500"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:69,question:"A debit balance of Nl50,000 in a cash account   shows   that   ",option:{a:"  cash  has   been overspent   by   N150,000   ",b:"  there   was N150,000 cash in hand ",c:" the total of cash received   was   less   than   N150,000   ",d:"N150,000 was the total of cash paid out. "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:384,question:"The concept applied in answering question 42 above is",option:{a:"matching",b:"consistency",c:"prudence",d:"entity"},section:" Use the following information to answer question: Branch stock account (at selling price)  D346,000 - debit Branch mark-up account D62,000 - debit",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:220,question:"The amount set aside out of profits earned by a company which are not meant for liability or contingency are",option:{a:"dividends",b:"provisions",c:"retained profits",d:"reserves"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:27,question:"The test of arithmetical accuracy of all postings in the ledger is provided in the: ",option:{a:"Journal  ",b:"Day book  ",c:"Cash book  ",d:"Trial balance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:489,question:"What is the net working capital?",option:{a:"N 2,600",b:"N1,800",c:"N 800",d:"N 600"},section:"Use the information to answer question: Total current assets [N2,000 ]; Total fixed assets [N 4,000 ]; Current liabilities [N 1,200 ]; Drawings [N 200 ]; Long-term loan 	[N 2,000 ]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:461,question:"I.    Facilitating the preparation of final accounts II.   Making the existence of error easy to detect III. Checking the accuracy of postings periodically. From the above, which of the following are among the uses of control accounts?",option:{a:"I, II and III",b:"I and III",c:"II and III",d:"I and II."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:390,question:"A collection of fields relating to one logically definable unit of business information is known as",option:{a:"data",b:"character",c:"byte",d:"record"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:118,question:"The prime cost is",option:{a:"GHc 64,500.",b:"GHc 64,000.",c:"GHc 58,500.",d:"GHc 52,500."},section:"Use the following information to answer question:  Stock of raw materials 1/1/09  [ 5,000 ], Stock of raw materials 31/12/09   [ 5,500], Purchase of raw materials [ 50,000], Carriage inwards [3,000], Direct labour [ 12,000], Factory overhead [17,500]",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:498,question:"Determine the gross profit",option:{a:"N 49,000",b:"N 48,000",c:"N 31,000",d:"N30,000"},section:"Use the information to answer questions: Work-in-progress 1/1[N 1,000 ];	Work-in-progress 31/12 	[N 2,000 ]; Production cost of goods manufactured 	[N 20,000 ] Sales [N 50,000]; Stock of finished goods 1/1 [N 4,000 ]; Stock of finished goods 31/12 [N 5,000 ]; Selling and distribution expenses[  N 2,000 ]; Administrative expenses [ 1,000 ]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:315,question:"The accounting entry to correct sales day book overcast is",option:{a:"debit Sales Account and credit Debtors Account",b:"debit Suspense Account and credit Sales Account",c:"debit Debtors Account and credit Suspense Account",d:"debit Sales Account and credit Suspense Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:230,question:"Whatever is fed into the computer is exactly what would be processed and produced as output. This is the concept of",option:{a:"sorting out",b:"last in, first out",c:"first in, first out",d:"garbage in, garbage out."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:358,question:"Which of the following is entered in the general journal?",option:{a:"Purchase of goods",b:"Sale of goods on credit",c:"Returns inwards",d:"Acquisition of fixed assets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:104,question:"Agreement between partners is contained in the Partnership",option:{a:"Act.",b:"Deed.",c:"Accord",d:"Deal."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:151,question:"The impersonal account is subdivided into",option:{a:"realand nominal accounts",b:"nominal and personal accounts",c:"real and current accounts",d:"personal and real accounts."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:81,question:"The lodgment of business cash into the business bank account is an example of",option:{a:"contra entry",b:"bank reconciliation",c:"self balancing ledger",d:"reversal entry"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:391,question:"The principle of double entry book - keeping states that",option:{a:"every debtor must have a creditor",b:"every account debited must be immediately credited",c:"for every debit entry, there must be a corresponding credit entry",d:"for every double debit, there must be a double credit."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:3,question:"Where a proprietor withdraws cash from the business for his private use, the entries would be ",option:{a:"credit cash account, debit proprietor's account ",b:"credit proprietor's account, debit cash account ",c:"credit proprietor's account, debit   drawings   account    ",d:"credit   cash account,  debit drawings account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:6,question:"Which of the following is the most liquid ",option:{a:"stock ",b:"debtors ",c:"machinery ",d:"loose tools"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:422,question:"Transfers from the head office to branches are best carried out at",option:{a:"cost price",b:"selling price",c:"cost plus mark-up",d:"market price"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:108,question:"The Public Accounts Committee is an organ of",option:{a:"military regime.",b:"parliament.",c:"presidency.",d:"councilors."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:307,question:"Assets acquired is recorded by debiting",option:{a:"Asset Account, crediting Cash Account",b:"Cash Account, crediting Asset Account",c:"Purchase of Business Account, crediting Sale of Business Account",d:"Asset Account, crediting Purchase of business Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:111,question:"Which of the following is not an item on the credit side of the purchases ledger control account?",option:{a:"Cash received",b:"Cash payment",c:"Contra settlement",d:"Cheque payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:288,question:"An increase in the provision for doubtful debts results in a/an",option:{a:"increase in the gross profit.",b:"decrease in the gross profit.",c:"decrease in the net profit.",d:"increase in the net profit."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:326,question:"In the balance sheet of a social club, subscription owing is treated as a",option:{a:"current liability",b:"current asset",c:"tangible asset",d:"long-term liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:43,question:"Which of the following would not be included in a balance sheet?",option:{a:"Accounts receivable",b:"Accounts payable  ",c:"Sales",d:"Cash"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:497,question:"The costs incurred by departments that support the production department with such activities as maintenance, production control and storage are called",option:{a:"autonomous costs",b:"service costs",c:"supporting costs",d:"subsidiary costs"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:389,question:"Which of the following is not a factory overhead cost?",option:{a:"Manufacturing wages",b:"Factory rent",c:"Depreciation of machinery",d:"Salary of factory guard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:359,question:"The cost of carriage outward is classified as",option:{a:"a selling and distribution expense",b:"an administrative expense",c:"a trading expense",d:"a finance expense"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:82,question:"credit balance is",option:{a:"a liability or an expense.",b:"a liability or an income.",c:"an expenditure or an income.",d:"an asset or an expense."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:200,question:"An expense becomes an accrual because it",option:{a:"is due for payment",b:"is a Profit and Loss Account item",c:"is a Trading Account item",d:"is to be paid within the next one year"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:509,question:"Provision for bad and doubtful debts in companies final accounts is treated in",option:{a:"trading account",b:"profit and loss account",c:"fund flow statement",d:"cash flow statement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:499,question:"What is the net profit?",option:{a:"N  46,000",b:"N 45,000",c:"N  28,000",d:"N  27,000"},section:"Use the information to answer questions: Work-in-progress 1/1[N 1,000 ];	Work-in-progress 31/12 	[N 2,000 ]; Production cost of goods manufactured 	[N 20,000 ] Sales [N 50,000]; Stock of finished goods 1/1 [N 4,000 ]; Stock of finished goods 31/12 [N 5,000 ]; Selling and distribution expenses[  N 2,000 ]; Administrative expenses [ 1,000 ]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:446,question:"The total amount of money received on application was",option:{a:"N  5600,00",b:"N  220,000",c:"N  800, 000",d:"N  1 000 000"},section:"A company’s authorized share capital was one million ordinary shares at N 1 each. It issued 80% of its shares at N 1.10 per share. 70k was payable on application, 25k on allotment, 10k due on first call and the balance on second call. ",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:408,question:"Determine how much to be charged to profit and loss account.",option:{a:"N 606",b:"N 786",c:"N 791",d:"N 856"},section:"Given: General expenses account Paid by cheque [ N671 ]; Paid by cash [N 70 ]; Accrued b/f [N 65 ] Accrued c/f [N 115 ]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:31,question:"Final accounts of a company refers to: ",option:{a:"Trading and profit and loss account  ",b:"Profit and loss account and balance sheet  ",c:"Trading account and balance sheet  ",d:"Trading , profit and loss account and balance sheet"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:506,question:"In partnership account, conversion of non-cash assets into cash 		is referred to as",option:{a:"realization",b:"disposal",c:"dissolution",d:"revaluation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:441,question:"Expenses paid during the conversion of a partnership to a 	company are",option:{a:"debited to the partners’ capital account",b:"debited to the realization account",c:"debited to the cash account.",d:"credited to the realization account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:514,question:"One of the reasons for the existence of the public sector is to",option:{a:"take adequate care of the needy",b:"supplement the commercial sector",c:"provide cheap services to all citizens",d:"correct perceived inequalities."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:344,question:"The quality of output information depends on the",option:{a:"quality of input data",b:"time of processing",c:"speed of processing",d:"quantity of output device"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:182,question:"The net book value at the time of sale was",option:{a:"N=  16,000",b:"N=  14,000",c:"N=  12,000",d:"N= 6,000."},section:"An asset was bought on 1st January, 1992 for N= 20,000. Depreciation was provided for annually at 20% on cost. It was sold for N= 7,000 on 1st July, 1995.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:318,question:"Unpresented cheques are cheque",option:{a:"that have been recorded in the cash book, but not by the bank",b:"that have been received by the bank, but recorded in the cash book",c:"returned by the bank",d:"written, but not handed over to customers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:209,question:"The amount of goodwill was",option:{a:"N  4,000",b:"N  3,000",c:"N  2,000",d:"N  1,000."},section:"A business whose assets consisted of stock  N 15,000 and debtors   N  8,000 was bought by issuing 20,000 ordinary shares of   N  1 each at a premium of  20 percent.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:374,question:"When shares are issued above their nominal value, the 	excess above the nominal value is",option:{a:"credited to Profit and Loss Account",b:"debited to Share Premium Account",c:"credited to Share Capital Account",d:"credited to share Premium Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:101,question:"The minimum number of persons required to form a partnership business is",option:{a:"2.",b:"3.",c:"5",d:"10."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:204,question:"Which of the following best describes the path of a transaction?",option:{a:"Source documents to Journal to Ledger",b:"Source documents to Ledger to Journal",c:"Journal to Ledger to source documents",d:"Journal to source documents to Ledger"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:291,question:"Shares of N3 nominal value were issued at a price of  N4. The difference of N1 is a",option:{a:"commission.",b:"discount.",c:"premium.",d:"bonus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:429,question:"Debentures can be redeemed out of",option:{a:"existing share capital reserve",b:"existing general reserve",c:"proceeds from new issue of shares",d:"withholding tax."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:29,question:"Accounting equation is given by  ",option:{a:"Assets - Liabilities + Owner's Equity ",b:"Assets = Liabilities - Owner's Equity ",c:"Assets + Owner's Equity = Liabilities ",d:"Assets = Liabilities + Owner's Equity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:297,question:"Administrative, selling and distribution expenses in a 	manufacturing firm are recorded in",option:{a:"Trading Account.",b:"Manufacturing Account.",c:"Profit and Loss Account.",d:"Balance Sheet."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:92,question:"The double entry principle states that",option:{a:"every debit entry must have a corresponding credit entry",b:"every credit entry must have a corresponding double entry",c:"every debit entry must have a corresponding double entry",d:"every asset must have a corresponding liability."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:491,question:"Using FIFO method, what is the value of the closing stock?",option:{a:"N 34,000",b:"N 29,000",c:"N 17,000",d:"N 12,000"},section:"Use the information to answer question: Jan. 1 Received 1,000 units at   N 10 each; Jan. 2 Received 2,000 units at   N  12 each; Jan. 3 Issued 1,500 units; Jan. 4 Received 1,000 units at   N  11 eac; Jan. 5 Issued 1000 units",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"}],n={message:e,subject:t,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,o as status,t as subject,i as total};
